Sanjay Kumar Sahu (1) Featured

Associate Tech Specialist seeking roles in UI/UX Development, Front End Design, ReactJS/Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, Photoshop, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, SVN, Git, JIRA, Technical Support, Agile and Scrum Methodology, Unit Testing, Requirement Gathering.



Current Designation: Associate Tech Specialist Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tech Mahindra Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: ui/ux development, front end design, javascript, jquery, photoshop, bootstrap, html, css, svn, git, jira, unit

testing,react.js,redux

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Understanding, analysis of the Business requirements and Project Planning, and providing Functional and Technical Support to team.

Expertise in HTML5, Jade, CSS3, Bootstrap, ReactJS/Redux, JavaScript, JQuery, Photoshop.

Experience in wireframe/prototype designing using Photoshop, Justinmind prototype.

Working on Agile and Scrum methodologies to accomplish project milestones according to specific time frame and requirement

Work Experience

Tech Mahindra as Associate Tech Specialist

Mar 2016 to Till Date

Understanding, analysis of the Business requirements and Project Planning, and providing Functional and Technical Support to team.

Expertise in HTML5, Jade, CSS3, Bootstrap, ReactJS, JavaScript, JQuery, Photoshop.

Experience in wireframe/prototype designing using Photoshop, Justinmind prototype.

Working on Agile and Scrum methodologies to accomplish project milestones according to specific time frame and requirement.

Nityo Infotech as GUI Developer Feb 2015 to Mar 2016

Inest Technologies as Software Engineer Jan 2012 to Feb 2015

Education

UG: B.Sc (Biology) from North Orissa University (NOU) in 2002

PG: MCA (Computers) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2005

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Adobe Photoshop, Justinmind, JQuery	
JavaScript, SVN, SourceTree, JIRA, Git,	
Html, Css, Ajax, Bootstrap, ReactJS,	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Oriya	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Cisco Matrix Client: Cisco Services

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Matrix is generic analytics framework developed by Cisco CX Services team which allows easy adaption to different kinds of data sources and allows to apply analytics functions in-built in the solution.

Matrix has following key capabilities, which allow to build or customize the use cases as per customers requirements.

Multi-Technologies / Multi-vendor Support, Customizations, Machine Learning, Automation.

Project Title: ATOMS System

Client: T-Mobile

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Apr 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The Project work is in association with the T-Mobiles Product called ATOMS System. ATOMS is the Automated Transport Order Management System in a SOX controlled environment that has the single source of record for Telco Circuit Lifecycle Management. The product is available in the form of web portal which interacts with various downstream systems.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time